(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-04T14:07:57.672690",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
うちら！
Us!
アソビ★まわり隊！だー！
Asobi★Mawari-tai!
のいちゃん！
Noi-chan!
お主らの声聞こえてるかーの？
Can you guys hear our voices?
聞こえてるかーの？
Can you hear us?
みんな！
Everyone!
大丈夫？今日子だけの声バカでかかったりしない？
Are you okay, Kyoko? Your voice was insanely loud!
一応確認してから来てんじゃがどうかな？どう？大丈夫かな？どうなんすか？
I made sure before coming, but... is it okay?
うん？
Hmm?
あっ、そういってみんな「たい」って言ってくれてる！
Oh, everyone's saying "tai" together!
やったー！一緒！ありがとー！うれしーね！
Together! Thank you!
早速、お主らがね、あの、ちゃんとご挨拶をしてくれて嬉しいですね！ありがとうございます！
First of all, Onushi gave us a proper greeting, so we're so happy! Thank you!
さて、ということでですね、ここまで4人、私たち4人が1人ずつ歌わくリレーやってまいりましたけれども、
So, with that said, up until now, all four of us sang solo songs, but...
お主らいかがでしたか？
Onushi, how was it?
どうだったかな？
How was it?
気になるね！
Everyone's wondering!
しかも、つづりと今日子はさ、歌うの初めてじゃよな？
And plus, Tsuzuri and Kyoko were singing together for the first time, right?
そうなんです！
That's right!
初後悔しちゃった。
It's my first time experiencing regret.
後悔じゃんね！
You regret it?!
つづりどうしたの？
Tsuzuri, what happened?
つづりは、まこと、つづりは……
Tsuzuri is... Tsuzuri is...
いや、でも楽しかったです！
Well, but it was fun, right?
楽しかった？
Was it fun?
楽しかった！
ごめん、今日子多分ね、下げすぎって言ってるんだけど、
Kyoko is probably saying it's too quiet, but...
あのね、私が横向いちゃうと、マイクに声が乗らない仕様なのよ。
If I turn sideways, my voice doesn't pick up on the mic.
あー、なるほど！
Ah, I see.
で、私みんなの目見すぎて話しすぎちゃって、横向いちゃうんだよね。
And I talked too much about everyone's eyes, so I end up turning sideways!
なるほど！ごめんね！
I see, sorry!
そう、今日はこういうマイクだからね。
That's why we have this mic today.
そう、今日こう言うマイク。
Today's mic...
これか、ちょっと、今日子のマイクが低いかなって思ってあげるの。
I thought Kyoko's mic was a bit low, so I raised it.
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
これで届きやすくなったかな？
It'll be easier to hear now!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
よしよしよしよし！
Okay, okay, okay!
つづり上手だったって言われてるよ！
They're saying Tsuzuri was really good!
ほんと？みんな褒めてるよ！ほら！
Really? Everyone's praising you!
やったー！ありがとう！嬉しいね、ほんとに！
Thank you so much!
ほら、かっこよかったって言ってる！つづりかっこよかったって！
Tsuzuri's singing was cool! Everyone's saying it was cool!
ほら、つづり最高って言ってるよ！つづり最高って！
Tsuzuri's the best! Everyone's saying Tsuzuri is the best!
楽しいな、歌うの。
It's fun to sing.
コメント読みながら歌うの楽しいよね、つづりね。うん、もうね！
Singing while reading comments is so much fun, Tsuzuri, right?
ということで、ちょっと今日のおおしながきを発表しちゃおうかなと思ってて。
So, we'd like to announce today's setlist!
今日、あの、私たち1人で歌ったんじゃが、今日はなんて、せっかく4人でこうやってね、揃ってるから、
Today we sang individually, but since the four of us are gathered together today,
4人でコラボ歌枠もやっちゃったりしようかなって思ってるんじゃが、
we were thinking of doing a four-person collab song as well!
しかも、しかも今日はなんとグループ分け？グループ分けして2人でコラボ歌枠みたいなのもしちゃおうかなとか思ってるんだけど、どうかな？
And what's more, we were thinking of splitting into groups of two for duets too! What do you think?
めっちゃいいじゃん！
That sounds amazing!
最高じゃん！最高！じゃあひらめき……
Saiko! Saiko! Time for inspiration!
やっていきたいと思います！
We're going to do it!
えっと、まず、えっと今日はちょっと、おしゃべり、おしゃべりをして、えっと、2人2人で歌って、そのあとまたおしゃべりして、4人で歌うって感じにしようって思ってるから、
First, we'll chat a bit, sing in pairs, chat again, and then sing as four.
お主ら、最後まで遊び回りたい、歌わくリレー、お見逃しな……
Onushi, we want to enjoy it until the very end, singing together!
泣く！ 泣く！
Cry! Cry!
そしてそして、あの、今見てくれてるお主ら、あの、みんなのチャンネル登録はお済んでおるかの？
And to all of you watching right now, have you subscribed to our channels yet?
おるかの！
You bet we have!
メンバー全員のほっかほかの新人のね、高評価とチャンネル登録と、そしてハッシュタグ「あそびまわりたい歌枠リレー」でツイートいっぱいしてほしいのじゃ！
We'd love it if you gave us a thumbs up, subscribed, and tweeted a lot under the hashtag "PlayAroundSongRelay"!
のじゃ！ ほしいのじゃ！
We want you to tweet!
そうするとね、わしら嬉しいからね。とっても嬉しい。
That'll make us super happy!
あのさっきもね、あの、あの他のこの歌を聞きながらめちゃめちゃ見てたからね、感想とかね。
We were listening to the other songs earlier and watching the chat too!
めちゃめちゃね、エゴサしてたよね。
We were totally fangirling!
ソフィあと、わしと二人でずっと見... エゴサの鬼がいた。前半組がずっと見てたんだよね。
Sophi and I were watching the whole first half!
というわけで、今日そういえばさ、お主ら秋葉原で昨日今日イベントあったの知ってる？
Which reminds me, did you guys know there was an event at Akihabara yesterday and today?
何があったよね、秋葉に！
Something happened in Akiba!
「あそびまわりたい」でさ、イベントがあってさ！
"Play Around" had an event!
しかも今日さ、あの、綴とソピアが、なんかサプライズで、
And get this, today Tsuzuri and Sopia had a surprise...
ゲスト、なになになんだけっけあれ、ゲリラ配信？ ゲリラ配信、うん。
Guerilla stream!
そう、あの現地の人とさ、こう意思疎通できるやつ、したって聞いたんじゃが。
We heard you could communicate with people there in person!
そうなんだよね！ めっちゃそこかったよね！
Is that true? It must've been packed!
本当にみんなの顔を直接見れてね、わあっていって本当やり取りとかもさせていただいて、すごく感動したなんか、本当にたくさんの方に応援頂いてるんだなってね。
Being able to see everyone's faces directly and chat with them really touched our hearts.
そう、本当にデビューしたんだなって改めて時間が空いてて、
We realized anew that we've debuted.
めっちゃ楽しかったね！
It was so much fun!
人間いたしの、いっぱいだよね。ね、お疲れ。
We got to meet so many people!
そう、あのめらっちとチョコは、あの昨日ね、ゲリラ配信してたんだよね。そう、Day 1にね。しょうさと
And Merach and Choco did a guerilla stream yesterday, right? On Day 1!
昨日、昨日は、あの、わし今日ってさ、割と匂わせしてたじゃん、昨日わしと今日子で。匂わせしたけど、昨日全く匂わせなしのガチサプライズじゃったから、
Yesterday, Choco and I did a broadcast together, but yesterday was a total surprise with zero hints!
びっくりしてたんでないの、お主ら。
You must have been so surprised!
みんな早かったよ。始まった瞬間にみんな、わーって来てくれて、たしかに！ すごかったんだから本当に。
Everyone was so fast! The moment it started, you all came rushing in!
なんかあの、テープみたいなので作られてるぐらい人集まってたよね。そうそうそうそう。
It was like they were printing tickets with a tape machine, so many people gathered!
確かに、今日、そうだね、めっちゃ痛いよね、本当にその音。
That's true, today... yeah, it hurt so much, really, both of us.
いいねえ。
That's great!
しかもあの、なんだっけ、あの、絶叫？ 絶叫じゃない、聖教？ 聖教過ぎて、あのコインランドリーポーチさ、そうそうそうそう。もう昼にはね、そうそうそうそうそう。
And what was it, "Zekkyo"? No, "Seikyo"? We went way past "Seikyo" straight to the coin laundry porch!
最初の方になくなっちゃったみたいな。
It sold out right at the very beginning!
本当にみんなやってくれてありがたいよね。
Everyone, thank you so much for doing that!
ねえ、噂を聞いてね。ソピア声ちっちゃい？ ソピア上げれるかの？ どうやって上げるんじゃ？
Sopia, is your voice small? Can Sopia be raised? How do we raise it?
ソピアのところを多分お、よいしょよいしょよいしょ。
Sopia's side is probably... a little higher, a little higher.
あ、ありがとう！ ちょっと大きくなったかも。
Ah, thank you! It got a little louder!
あ、ありがとう！
Ah, thank you!
あ、聞こえる！
Ah, I can hear it!
あ、聞こえる聞こえる。あ、ソピアだ！ あ、ソピアだ！ トマトも、わーい！
It's Sopia! Sopia! Yay!
そう、それでさ、あの、スタンプさ、全部集めたけど、あの、交換できなかった人とかもきっといると思うんじゃが、
So, we collected a bunch of stamps, but I'm sure there were some people who couldn't exchange theirs.
でもね、そんだけね、大人気ってことはきっとその頑張り、その大人気さ、あそびまわりたいの人気さをきっと、あの全世界が見てくれてるってことだから、きっと次もね、次に繋がるはずじゃと、思うんじゃよ。
Even so, the fact that it was so popular means that all your hard work and popularity... the popularity of "Play Around" is definitely being watched by the whole world!
繋がる！ 繋がる！
It's connecting! It's connecting!
だからさ、すごいのがさ、こうちなくなったよってお知らせが出た後にも、まだ全然スタンプラリーやって下さる方が、いっぱいいてさ！ そうそうそうそうそう。ありがとう！
And what's amazing is that even after the notice that Kochi was gone came out, people still came to do Stamp Rally! Thank you so much!
ね、嬉しい！
We're so happy!
ね、めちゃくちゃありがたいよね。ね。しかも楽しかったって。そうそうそうそう。よかった！
It's super appreciated, and it was so much fun!
うん、嬉しいの。本当ね、こういう声のおかげでね、また私たちの次なる企画がね、そうそうそうイベントだったりとか、そういうのが生まれるので、
We're so happy, and thanks to voices like yours, our next projects and events will be born!
ねえ、本当にみんなから応援いただいて、ありがたかったね今回は本当に。
Thank you so much to everyone for cheering us on this time!
本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
ショッパーもいっぱい手に入れてくれてありがとうなのじゃ！ ありがとう！
Thank you for getting so many books and everything!
うーん。嬉しかったの。
We're so happy!
ふん。あ、あとさ、あとさ、楽しくなっちゃうんだけど、あの今日の配信でわしら決めたいことあるんだよね。
And also, we want to decide on something during today's stream!
ある！ うん、本当は前のコラボ配信で決めたかったんだけどさ、
There is! We actually wanted to decide this during the last collab stream, but...
時間がね！ 時間がね！ うんうんうん。
We ran out of time!
あ、そう、楽しすぎてね、ごめんなさい！
It was just too much fun! Sorry!
そう、何を決めたいかというと、結局あそびまわりたいの略称って何んなんじゃ？ なんんなんじゃ？ 何んなんじゃ結局。
So, what do we want to decide? Well, what does the abbreviation for "Play Around" even mean anyway?
そう、なんかいろんなさ、候補があったじゃろ。なんじゃっけ、なんか綴りわけわかんないこと言ってたやつあったよね。あの恐ろしいやつね。わかんないあれ。
Right! There were all kinds of proposals, weren't there? Like, what was that thing where Tsuzuri was saying things that made no sense?
え、違うよ、あれさ、今日子がなんか逆々って言われてたからさ、私あそびまわりたいを逆に、なんか返ってDeepLしたらなんか、つーちゃんがおかしいみたいなのってびっくりしたんだよね、あれ。
Wait, no, that was different! Kyoko said "Gyakugyaku", so we thought if we went to DeepL for "Play Around", it would come out like "Tsu-chan is weird" or something, and we were so surprised!
解説聴いても分かんないよ！ 解説聴いても分かんないのじゃ！ ぴったびそうは。
Even after listening to the explanation, I still didn't get it!
気になった人はちょっとTwitterで
If you're curious, check out our Twitter
私たちのツイート遡っていただいたらいの
and trace back our past tweets...
結構前だよね。デビュー前?
That was quite a while ago. Before debut?
デビュー前! めっちゃ前。
Before debut! Super early.
で、あの、この略称を配信の途中で決めようと思ってるから
And we're planning to decide on this abbreviation during the stream,
あの、お前ら考えといて。
so you guys better think of one beforehand!
いい略称考えといて。私たちたちがね、歌ってる間に、あの、お前らたちに考えとってもらおうかなって。
Think of a good abbreviation. While we're singing, we'll have you guys think of some for us!
なんかとか候補出す?そしたら。
We can give some candidates, right?
確かに、確かに。
True, true.
何がいいかあの、うちでさ、いいなって言ってたのは
What was good... what we thought was nice earlier was
あそびた。あ、あそびた!
"Asobita." Ah, "Asobita!"
あとは、あのソピアのひらめきでえっと遊びたいとかあそまわとか。あそまわ?
And from Sopia's inspiration, things like "Asobitai" or "Asomawa." "Asomawa"?
あそまわもいいね。あ、え?
"Asomawa" is nice too. Ah, eh?
綴りてきの結構先輩も言ってくださってた、「あたい」って結構好きなんだよね。
Tsudzuri-teki's—senpai also mentioned it—I really like "Atai."
あたい!あたい!うち、あたいよ!
"Atai!" "Atai!" Us, it's "Atai!"
いやち、あ、あたいよ!混乱しちゃう。
No, we are "Atai!" I'm getting confused.
「あたい」ってなんか略し方オタク略しみたいなのじゃん。
"Atai" feels like an otaku-style abbreviation.
アニメのね、そのアニメのオタクの略しみたいなの。
Like, an otaku abbreviation for an anime title.
と、としこり?
And "Toshikori"?
そっかそっか。確かに。
I see, I see. True.
みたいな候補がね?
Something like that as a candidate, right?
あとさ、こより先輩が考えてくれた、あまったいも素敵だよね。
And Koyori-senpai's suggested "Amatai" is also wonderful, right?
あまったい可愛いよね。あまったい可愛い。すごい可愛い。
"Amatai" is cute, right? "Amatai" is cute. Super cute.
みたいな。ほかにもね、みんな思いついたらひらめいたらぜひぜひね、またチャットしてもらえると嬉しいです。
Like that. If anyone else thinks of or comes up with something, we'd love for you to chat it to us.
教えてほしいのじゃーん。お願いします。
Tell us, please!
さてさて、ここまでちょっとおしゃべりしてたけど、さっきまでやっぱ歌わくしたしそろそろ和たちの歌、お姉ら聞きたいんじゃないの?
Now, we've been chatting a bit up to here, but since we had singing streams earlier, don't you guys want to hear us sing?
聞きたい!
We want to hear it!
今日が、お姉らが歌うんだよ! 私たちか?
Today, we are the ones singing! Us?
そうだよ! 私たちが歌うんだよ! そっか!
That's right! We are going to sing! Oh right!
聞きたいじゃろ?
You want to hear it, right?
あのね、チーム分けしてきたんだよね、今回。
You know, we split into teams this time.
どうやってチーム分けしたか教えてあげる?
Want us to tell you how we split the teams?
じゃあ、考えてもらおうか、ちょっと。
Well then, let's have you guess for a bit.
あ、確かに!確かに、確かに合わせでしょうっていう。どういうチームでしょ?
Ah, true! "Match them up properly," right? What kind of teams are they?
4人でね、その22で分かれたんじゃけど、誰と誰で分かれたと思う?
The four of us split into two and two—who do you think split with whom?
誰と誰だ?誰と誰だ?
Who and who? Who and who?
なんか私達の中で、なんかチーム名みたいなのもジャカ決まってるん、呼びながらね。そう呼びながらやるんじゃけど、なんじゃと思う?
Among us, the team names are kinda already decided while calling out. We'll do it while calling them, but what do you think they are?
すっごい簡単な分け方をしたよ、うちらね。まあ、そうね。
We used a super simple way of splitting! Well, yeah.
なんじゃと思う?1日目、2日目だって。最新順ね。なるほどね。確かにはい、1日目さんみたいなのね。
What do you think? Day 1, Day 2. Chronological order. I see, I see. True, like Day 1-san.
え、なんかさ、みんなすごくさ、鋭くない?
Eh, like, aren't you guys all super sharp?
ひらめいてる。
You're inspired.
ボケとツッコミとか書いてある。
Someone wrote "Boke and Tsukkomi."
え、ボケとツッコミだったら何?どう当てはまる?
Eh, if it's Boke and Tsukkomi, what is it? How does it fit?
え、ま、綴りと、きょ、きょーこがツッコミで、綴りと京子がツッコミでじゃないの?逆だろ!
Eh, well, Tsudzuri and Kyo—Kyouko is the tsukkomi, wait, isn't Tsudzuri and Kyouko the tsukkomi? Got it reversed!
あ、やっつけちゃったでも。
Ah, you beat us to it though.
じゃあ、私ボケじゃんその場合。え、じゃあ何?ボケが綴り一人だったような可能性?
Then I'm the boke in that case. Eh, then what? Is there a possibility that Tsudzuri was the only boke?
いや、私は積極的にボケていくよ。確かに、京子もボケてる。
No, I actively act as the boke. True, Kyouko is also a boke.
確かに。じゃ、ボケ組とツッコミ組か。
True. Then Boke-gumi and Tsukkomi-gumi.
で、ボケ組?
And, Boke-gumi?
そうだよ、つーちゃんこっちおいで?
That's right, Tsu-chan, come over here!
人と人外だて、確かに。
Human and non-human, true.
それもある、人間とそうじゃないものがいるの。確かに、確かに。
That's also a thing, there are humans and non-humans. True, true.
年齢とやばい方だって。
Age and dangerous side, it says.
えっ?えっ?年齢とやばい方、ま、両方綴りか。
Eh? Eh? Age and dangerous side—well, both are Tsudzuri.
え、なんでよ!おかしいでしょ!一人しか該当しない。ままチームだ。
Eh, why! That's weird! Only one person fits. Mama team.
え、1対3ってこと?
Eh, meaning 1 vs 3?
1対3じゃちょっと生々意味ないの。
1 vs 3 is a bit too realistic/meaningless.
あ、そうそうそう。やっぱ2対2がいいもんね。
Ah, right right right. 2 vs 2 is better after all.
で、つーちゃんつーちゃん今、お姉さん組とポン組って書いてあったけど、これどういう分け方かな?
And Tsu-chan Tsu-chan, it currently says Onee-san-gumi and Pon-gumi, but what kind of splitting is this?
いや、さすがに、綴りかお姉さんでさ。
Well, as expected, Tsudzuri is an Onee-san.
答えはえーと、響子と綴り、そしてメーラとソピアで分かれてるんじゃが。
The answer is, um, Kyouko and Tsudzuri, and Mella and Sopia are separated.
男色さん!
Danshoku-san!
はーい! 寒色さん!
Haa-i! Kanshoku-san!
はーい! 暖色さん!
Haa-i! Danshoku-san!
色で分けておりますのじゃー。
Separated by colors!
うちら背の順とかさ、色分けとかさ、なんかめちゃ単純なのおくない?
For us, height order, color coding, aren't they super simple?
いや、そうなんだよ。
Well, that's true.
だからさ、仲良し組でさ、分けようとしても分けらんないじゃん、正直。
So even if we try to split by close-friend groups, we can't really split them, honestly.
それもそうかも。そうかも、そうかも。
That might be true too. True, true.
仲良しで22に分けらんないからさ、うちら4人だからさ、必然的にそうなっちゃうよね。
Since we can't split 2-2 by best friends, there's 4 of us, so it naturally ends up like that.
確かに 確かに
Indeed, indeed.
ということで、今日は男色さんからお歌を歌ってもらおうかなって思うので、
So today, I thought we'd have Danshoku-san sing a song,
まず一旦歌うお部屋に移動してもよいかの。
so shall we first move to the singing room?
お部屋！
The room!
ま、移動してマイクの本数が変わるだけなんですが。
Well, we're just moving so the mic count changes.
私たちが横にずれるから、
Since we're shifting to the side,
よいしょ。
heave-ho.
歌う2人が真ん中にいてもらいたくて、マイクちょっと待っての。
we want the two singers in the middle—wait a second for the mic.
うんと、これで。
Um, with this.
あれ、つーちゃんこれさ、あの息合わせってさ。
Hey, Tsu-chan, about timing our breaths...
どーもー！
Hello!
つーじ、もっと端っこから行かなきゃダメじゃん。
Tuji, you gotta start more from the edge!
の、どーもー！
Uh, hello!
男色さんチームでーす！
We're Team Danshoku!
何？漫才始まる？
What? Is a comedy routine starting?
やばい、つぼずらせでやろうぜ。やばい...
Oh no, let's stagger our pots. Oh no...
いや、1回やってみたかったんだよね、これ。
Man, I've wanted to try this at least once.
確かにちょっと憧れではあったよ。
True, it was kind of an aspiration.
でさ、今日できたじゃん、やった！
And today we did it, yay!
え、嬉しい！
Yay, I'm so happy!
じゃあ、男色さんチームにお歌を歌ってもらおうと思うので、なんて曲を歌うか教えてもらってもいいかな？
So, since we'll have Team Danshoku sing a song, could you tell us what song you'll be singing?
ハッピーすっじゃん？
Happy Sugar?
行くよ。
Here we go.
せーの、デパーチャー！
Ready, set, Departure!
大地を踏みしめて
Treading firmly on the earth,
君は目覚めていく
you begin to awaken.
天使の微笑みで
With an angel's smile,
連れ出して！
lead me away!
孤独でも一人じゃないさ
Even in loneliness, you're not alone.
生まれてきたことに必ず意味がある
There is always a meaning to being born.
優しさに満ち溢れてる
Overflowing with kindness,
青い地球にありがとう
thank you to the blue earth.
You can smile again 太陽浴びて
You can smile again, bathing in the sun,
You can fly away 世界は君の輝きを待ってる
You can fly away, the world is waiting for your radiance.
大地を踏みしめて
Treading firmly on the earth,
君は目覚めていく
you begin to awaken.
天使の微笑みで連れ出して！
Lured out by an angel's smile!
“始まり”はいつでも遅くないさ
"Beginnings" are never too late,
何度でも立ち上がれ！
stand up as many times as it takes!
最後まであきらめないさ
Never give up until the very end.
やり続けることに必ず意味がある
There is always a meaning in keeping on.
You just try again 闇を抜けて
You just try again, passing through the darkness,
You just go away 未来はいつも僕たちを待ってる
You just go away, the future is always waiting for us.
大空駆け抜けて
Rushing through the open skies,
雲原超えてゆけ
crossing over the sea of clouds.
天使の投げキス捕まえて
Catching an angel's flying kiss,
まだ誰も見たことない世界へ飛び出そう明日へ
let's leap toward tomorrow into a world no one has ever seen.
大地を踏みしめて
Treading firmly on the earth,
飛び出そう明日へ
let's leap toward tomorrow!
大地を踏みしめて 君は目覚めていく
Treading firmly on the earth, you begin to awaken.
天使の微笑みで連れ出して 終わらない冒険に
Lured out by an angel's smile into an endless adventure!
出掛けよう いつまでもどこまでも
Let's set out, forever and ever.
流れ落ちる涙 勇気に変えていく
Turning falling tears into courage,
天使の羽広げ舞い上がれ 悲しみも痛みも包み込んで
spreading angel wings and soaring up, embracing both sorrow and pain.
強くなれ明日
Grow stronger, tomorrow!
大地を踏みしめて
Treading firmly on the ground,
強くなれ明日は
grow stronger for tomorrow!
君は目覚めていく
You are awakening
天使の微笑みで
with an angel's smile,
連れ出して
lead me away!
始まりはいつでも遅くないさ
It's never too late to start over.
何度でも！
No matter how many times!
何度でも立ち上がれ！
Rise up over and over!
強化系...
Enhancement type...
今日子、星流、メルエムよあれは
Kyoko, Seira, that's Meruem!
星流はうぼぉぎんよ
Seira is Uvogin!
強化系、強化系の...はぁってやつ
The "Haa!" of the enhancement type.
めっちゃ強いやつね
The super strong guy.
ここだけきまらんとへんな...
Only this part went weird...
ハンターハンターのね、曲をね、歌いましたと。
We sang a Hunter x Hunter song.
じゃあ、そろそろ私たちも歌っちゃおうかな？
Well, shall we sing ours soon too?
無茶息息炎炎炎炎... マイク高いのじゃ！
Endless fiery breathing... The mic is too high!
2人はどうもってやらなくて大丈夫？
Don't you need to do the intro?
やりたい！セフィア！やりたい！わかった！
I want to! Sephia! I want to! Got it!
どうも！感触組でございまーす！サラシナセフィアでーす！
Hello! We're the tactile group! I'm Sarashina Sephia!
どっちがボケ？ それは... どっちだ？
Which one is the funny one? That is... which?
いつもこの2人なんか争いやってるのじゃ！
These two are always arguing!
メラチとすんなら、まあセフィアがボケでいいかな？
If it's with Melati, maybe Sephia can be the funny one?
誰でやったらダメなの？ そりゃ綴りとならね...
Who shouldn't you be with? Well, with Tsuzuri...
噛んだ噛んだ噛んだ！今噛んだぞ！セフィア、ポンなんだから！
You stumbled! You stumbled! Sephia is such a ditz!
揚げ足取りがひでえのじゃ！もうええわ！
You're picking on me too much! Oh well!
おいちょっとよ... まだこれからなのじゃ！歌ってほしい！
Hey wait... We're still not done! Sing for us!
歌って歌って！じゃあ、私たちが歌う曲、せーの！で言う？
Sing, sing! Shall we say our song on three?
せーの！うまぴょい伝説！
Ready, go! Umapyoi Densetsu!
コールもね、2人に担当してもらうんだよね。
You two will handle the calls too, right?
(うまっち！) うー (うまいよ!)
(Umacchi!) Ooh (Delicious!)
うまっち！ うー
Umacchi! Ooh
うまぴょい！うまぴょい！うー
Umapyoi! Umapyoi! Ooh
好きだっち！ うーうまぴょい！
I love you! Ooh, Umapyoi!
うま、うま、うま、うまさん、に、いち、Fight!
Uma, uma, uma, uma, san, ni, ichi, Fight!
朝ぱっぱか快晴レース ちょこちょこ何気に
A brisk, sunny race, casually bustling along,
第1、第2、第3、第4、第5
1st, 2nd, 3rd, 4th, 5th,
メンタもギラギラ疾走で 今日もめちゃめちゃだ！
dashing with dazzling eyes, today is totally wild!
ガチ追い込み！推し勝つぞ！食い食いてえ！
A fierce final spurt! My favorite will win! I want to eat!
でもお休みにしたい あの子もこの子もどいつもこいつも
But everyone just wants to take a break,
泣かないで 試くんじゃねえ 赤チン塗っても
Don't cry, don't try testing it, even if you put medicine on it—
きょうの勝利の女神は あたしだけにチュッする
Today's goddess of victory gives a kiss only to me,
虹の彼方へゆこう 2人の彼方へゆこう
Let's go beyond the rainbow, beyond the two of us!
風を切って大地けて きみのなかに光ともす
Cutting through the wind, striking the earth, lighting a fire within you!
きみの愛馬が づきゅんどきゅん走り出し
Your beloved horse starts running with a thumping heart,
ばきゅんぶきゅんかけてゆくよ こんなレースは
Dashing away with a bang, a race like this
はじめて (3, 2, 1, Fight!)
Is a first for me! (3, 2, 1, Fight!)
づきゅんどきゅん胸が鳴り ばきゅんぶきゅん好きだよ
My heart pounds, I love you so much,
今日も叶えてる はぴはぴだりんさんにいちごーFight!
Making dreams come true today too, happy-happy darling!
うぴうぴはにーさんにおいちー うっほー！いー！
Upi-upi honey, delicious, ooh-hoo!
うまっち！ うー (うまぴょいうまぴょい)
Umacchi! Ooh (Umapyoi, Umapyoi)
吸ったかだったったったった (3, 2, 1, Fight!)
Inhaling it all up (3, 2, 1, Fight!)
ねむい 世紀の覚醒 近くで遠い
Sleepy, the awakening of the century, near yet far,
いななきダッシュ！国中ジャンプ！これって無敵の
Neighing dash! Jumping across the country! This invincible
あさぜえ攻めカワ水着で制服パジャマ
Morning-attacking cute swimsuit and school uniform pajamas!
あたいは本命 1点でお願い 抜くんじゃねえ 赤チン塗っても
I'm the favorite, I beg you for just one point, don't slack off even if you get hurt—
今日のステージの女神は あたしだけにチュッする
Today's stage goddess gives a kiss only to me,
虹の彼方へゆこう 2人の彼方へゆこう
Let's go beyond the rainbow, beyond the two of us!
汗をぬぐい涙拭いて きみのなかで闇を照らす
Wiping away sweat and tears, illuminating the darkness within you!
ズキュン ドキュン 走り出し
Running out with a dokyun dokyun heartbeat,
ばきゅん ぶきゅん かけていくよ
I'm dashing off with a bakyun bukyun!
こんな想いは はじめて
These feelings are all so new to me.
3, 2, 1, Fight!
ズキュン ドキュン 胸が鳴り
My heart beats with a dokyun dokyun,
ばきゅん ぶきゅん 大好きだよ
I love you with a bakyun bukyun!
今日も奏でる はぴはぴだーりん
Playing our happy-happy darling tune today too,
うっぴうっぴはにー 3, 2, 1, Go Fight!
Uppy-uppy honey, 3, 2, 1, Go Fight!
さあ盛り上がってまいりました！
Now, the excitement is building up!
はいはい！おすしくん隊 大安吉日
Yes, yes! Sushi-kun troop on a lucky day,
ぴぴわっしょいほいほい なりきりクイーン 黒坂ひかき
Pipi-wasshoi hoihoi, cosplay queen Kurosaka Hikaki!
高坂めきき
Takasaka Mekiki!
ぴーた団 投げたら返ってきた 朝練中止で
Tossed the Peter gang and it came back, morning practice cancelled,
スピードびーふぁー 走ったあとに ソーダ水 (爆死) たのしかったー！
Speed be-fur, after running, soda water (epic fail), it was so fun!
「そうだ、あとだしじゃんけんしよー」
"That's right, let's play delayed rock-paper-scissors!"
「だっさなきゃまけよ、じゃんけんしょい！」
"If you don't put it out you lose, rock-paper-scissors shoi!"
この気持ち届くなら 君のいろに染まるよ
If these feelings reach you, I'll be dyed in your colors.
こんなあたしじゃ だめだよねー
A girl like me just won't do, right?
ばっきゅーん！！ズキュンドキュン走り出し (うー、ふっふー！)
Bakyuun!! Running out with a dokyun dokyun (Uu, fuffuu!)
ズキュン ドキュン 走り出し
Running out with a dokyun dokyun,
ばきゅん ぶきゅん かけていくよ
Dashing off with a bakyun bukyun!
こんな想いは はじめて (3, 2, 1, Fight!)
These feelings are all so new (3, 2, 1, Fight!)
ズキュン ドキュン 胸が鳴り
My heart beats with a dokyun dokyun,
ばきゅん ぶきゅん 大好きだよ
I love you with a bakyun bukyun!
今日も奏でる はぴはぴだーりん
Playing our happy-happy darling tune today too,
うっぴうっぴはにー 3, 2, 1, Go Fight!
Uppy-uppy honey, 3, 2, 1, Go Fight!
ズキュン ドキュン 走り出し
Running out with a dokyun dokyun,
ばきゅん ぶきゅん かけていくよ
Dashing off with a bakyun bukyun!
こんな想いは はじめて (3, 2, 1, Fight!)
These feelings are all so new (3, 2, 1, Fight!)
ズキュン ドキュン 胸が鳴り
My heart beats with a dokyun dokyun,
ばきゅん ぶきゅん 大好きだよ
I love you with a bakyun bukyun!
今日も奏でる はぴはぴだーりん
Playing our happy-happy darling tune today too,
うっぴうっぴはにー 3, 2, 1, Go Fight!
Uppy-uppy honey, 3, 2, 1, Go Fight!
うっぴうっぴはにー 3, 2, 1, Fight!
Uppy-uppy honey, 3, 2, 1, Fight!
どうしよう、なんか…
What should I do...
どうしたの？二人手がめっちゃ可愛いと思って聞いてたのにさ、
What's wrong? I was listening thinking you two looked so cute,
ふとさ、歌ってる時にコメント欄見たら、「今日のえのきテパカー」
but then when I looked at the chat while singing, it said "Today's enoki tepakaー"!
違う！
No!
だって二人が可愛いからさ、ふたりうわあってなっちゃってさ！
Because you two were so cute, I was just like, whoa!
わかるわかる、めっちゃ可愛かったの、すまんね、超可愛かった。
I know, I know, it was super cute. Sorry, it was ultra cute.
メラチとソピアのオタクですまんねｗ
Sorry for being Merachi and Sopia's otaku lol
ありがとう！
Thank you!
うまぴょい伝説を伸ばせていただきました、のいちゃん！
You let us perform Umapyoi Legend, Noi-chan!
いぇーい！
Yay!
じゃあ二人とも上に登ってこれるかの、にょきにょきと。
So can both of you climb up on top, all nyoki-nyoki?
にょき？にょき？にあ、にょき？
Nyoki? Nyoki? Nya, nyoki?
あ、にょき、にょき。
Ah, nyoki, nyoki.
あ、じゃあ二人の方行く？
Ah, should we go to your side?
あ、そうしようか。
Ah, let's do that.
のいちゃん！
Noi-chan!
マイクの高さどうですか皆さん？
How is the microphone height, everyone?
我々がもっと上がればいいの？ずいずいずいずい
Should we go higher? Zui-zui-zui-zui
これくらいか？
About this much?
いい感じだ？
Feels good?
いい感じか？いい感じだ。
Feels good? Feels good.
よし、APGM！のいちゃん！
Alright, APGM! Noi-chan!
お主らどうだった？どうだった？
How was it for you guys? How was it?
コラボ歌うの初めてなんじゃない？
Isn't this your first time singing a collaboration?
ね、22初めてだよね？うんうん。
Right, it's our first time together, right? Yeah, yeah.
どうなんだ、どにゃん、どうだった？
How was it, Donyan, how was it?
え、どうだったかな。やばい、もう記憶が飛んでしまって、今日のてのご、ごめんなさい、つもっちゃった！
Um, how was it. Oh no, my memory just flew away, today's tenogo, sorry, I tripped up!
3、2、1、Fight!
3, 2, 1, Fight!
しかも今日のでっかい！
Plus today's was huge!
もう色々貫通して脳内に直接来るような、もうなんか物理的に…
It pierced through everything right into our brains, physically...
いやもうライブのつもりでやってるからさ、ね？
Well, we're doing it with the mindset of a live show, right?
でもさ、よく太り噛まなかったね、あれ綴りだったら無理だったかも。
But man, you didn't stutter much, if it were spelling it might've been impossible.
難しいすぎるよね。
It's way too hard, right?
めちゃ難しよね！しかも息もぴったりだったよ。
It's super hard! Plus our breathing was totally in sync.
息も合ってた！よかった！
Our breathing matched! Great!
よかったのいちゃん！
That's great, Noi-chan!
え、ちょっと感じゃったな、しゃべりでなくて。
Uh, I choked a bit there, not in speech though.
あ、大丈夫、気づいてるから。
Ah, it's fine, we noticed.
あ、ばれてなかった？あ、ばれてなかったよ。
Ah, wasn't it noticed? Ah, it wasn't noticed.
ホールに本気すぎてね。
Because we were too serious about the hall.
でも確かに、記憶の、だめだもう、やばい思い出したら狂っちゃう！
But really, my memory, no wait, if I remember it I'll go crazy!
全力ゴールじゃったから。
Because it was a full-power goal.
なんかさ、あの、私たち今さ、横に実際ね、いるんだよね。
You know, we are actually right next to each other right now.
今, あのオフ、オフコラボってやつ？オフコラボ！
Right now, that off, off-collab thing? Off-collab!
オフコラボなんじゃが、あの、うるさいんじゃよ。
It's an off-collab, but man, they're so loud.
声が、もう、うるさくてうるさくて、声がでかくて！
Their voices are just so, so loud, their voices are huge!
あれ、どのくらいでかいかっていうと、4人で喋ってんじゃん。なんかわからないけど、私が話した後だっけ、なんか部屋がね、キーンって音する。
Like, how loud is it? There are 4 of us talking. For some reason, after I speak or something, the room makes a ringing "kiiin" sound.
私が喋った後だけ、なんかキーンって言うんだよね。
Only after I speak, it makes that "kiiin" sound.
そうそうそう、あの、貫通して、そこまで来てくれたら。
Yeah, yeah, if it pierces through and reaches over there.
そうなんじゃよねえ。
That's right.
こんなでかいんだ。なんか普段さ、あの、今日この配信とかさ、見てる時はさ、やっぱあの、音量下げれるじゃん。
It's this big. You know, when watching today's stream and stuff normally, you can turn down the volume.
確かにね、確かに、なんかある程度下げて聞いてる。
True, true, we listen with it turned down to a certain extent.
生だと下げれないから
Because you can't lower it when it's live.
ねえ、ダイレクトアタック
Hey, a direct attack.
あれあのさ、ライブに行く時にやっぱ海外の人とかだと、もっと日本より音が大きいのでライブ。
When going to live shows overseas, the sound is often much louder than in Japan.
だから耳壊さないように
So, to avoid damaging your ears,
イヤホン入れてくのよ。耳栓みたいなの。
you put in earphones. Like earplugs.
そうそうそうそう。京子に会うときそれ必須かも。
That's right. That might be essential when meeting Kyoko.
京子グッズでグッズで耳栓出して。あ、出そう！
Kyoko, sell earplugs as merchandise! Oh, let's do that!
私と会うとき用さ。ありがとうございます。
For when people meet me. Thank you very much.
カバーさんおお願いします。のーしゃーん。
Cover Corp, please. No-shan!
そして、あの
And then, you know,
歌をね、あの聴いてもらったところで、お主ら歌聞きながら、ま歌きに夢中で忘れ得たかもしれないんだが、
songs are great, but while listening to songs, you might get so absorbed that you forget things.
略称ね、遊び回りの略称を考える話があったんだが、
We had talked about thinking of nicknames for playing around.
覚えているか、考えた？
Remember? Did you think of it?
え、どうやって決める？そもそも。
How do you decide, anyway?
アンケート？
A survey?
アンケートにさ、なんか闇鍋みたいに一個さ、変なの入れて。
Like putting something weird in a survey, like Yaminabe?
あ、ちょっと！それTsuchanのやつじゃん！
Hey, that's Tsuchan's idea!
それになったらみんなの世界観それになったらどうするんですか？
If that becomes the official name, what happens to everyone's world-building?
確かに！ちょっといったんアンケートを新しくするか。
True. So let's rethink the survey.
いや、うちら遊び回りたいだからさ、多分リスナーさんとかもそういう遊びもっと入れたいとか思うから危ないよそれ。
Since we want our play around to be fun, listeners might also want that kind of freedom, so it's dangerous!
あるよ、あるよ、全然あるよ。じゃあ4択まで選べっっぽいから
True, definitely. So, we can choose up to 4 options.
ちょっとこの4つに何入れるかをさ、おれたちでさ、考えよう。
Let's think together about what to put in those 4 choices.
遊びちょっとわし打ち込んでるからさ、むしろしゃべってて。
Since we're putting our hearts into playing, please speak up!
やっぱ「あそびたば」ほしいな。「あそびたば」ほしいね。なんかビタミンみたいな感じですごい好き。
I want Asomitabu! It's like a vitamin, I really like it.
ひらがなで「あそびた」？「あそびた」？「あそびた」めちゃ好き。ちゅーちゃんは？
In hiragana, "Asobita"? "Asobita"? I really like "Asobita".
やっぱ「あたい」がいいな。「あたい」ね。「あたい」だよ。
Atai is good. Atai is good.
「あたい」はカタカナの「あにたい」でいいかぬ。「あたい」「あたい」
Atai should just use the katakana "atai" (or with an exclamation mark).
え、びっくりマークのこし？「あたい！」びっくりマーク？
Wait, with an exclamation mark? "Atai!"?
「あたい」「あたい」入れよう。「あそびた」と「あたい」入れてるのね。あともう二個どうする？この貴重な二枠。
Wait, "Atai"? Let's include "Atai". And "Asobita" and "Atai".
ソフィアは？
Sophia, what about you?
えっとね、「あそまわ」かな。「あそまわ」いいね。「あそまわ」おーどでかわいいよね。全部ひらがなでいい？
"Asomawa"? "Asomawa" is cute, right? All in hiragana?
いや、「あそ」だけカタカナで「まわ」はひらがなとかどうだ？
Only "aso" in katakana and "mawa" in hiragana?
わかってる、わかってるソフィアやっぱり。
I get it, Sophia is amazing!
「あそまわ」がひらがな、めちゃくちゃいい。
"Aso-mawa" in hiragana is great too.
え、ファンの人からも聞きたいよね。
I want to hear from fans too.
あ、確かに。でも結構やっぱみんな「あまたい」をしてるね。
True. But many people are using "Amatigai" (Milky Way).
「あまたい」「あまだい」みたいな。漢字で「天台」がいる。漢字で「天台」がいる。
"Amatidai"? Like Milky Way?
あ、「あそまわ」も結構いそうだよ。ね、「あそまわ」もいるね。
"Asomawa" is also quite popular.
そのアンケートに入ってないやつの中だと多分「あまだい」が多そうかなっていう。
If it's not in the survey, "Amatidai" might be the most popular.
「あまだい」いる。「アリアンタイ」って言われてる。「アリアンタイ」どこから？どこから来た？
"Amatidai"... "Alien-tai"? Where did that come from?
どこですか？違います、遊び回りたいです。「アリアンタイ」じゃないです。
Where is it from? It's different, I want to play around! Not "Alien-tai"!
あの「アリアン」の1人だけだからね。
Wait, "Alien" only has one person, right?
ソフィアあれかも、声ちっちゃいのね。マイクもっとこれぐらい近づくんだよ。
Sophia, maybe your voice is too quiet? Get closer to the mic!
おっし、おっし。こんな問題どうでしょう。食べる勢いだから、マイクって食べていいんだよ。
How's this? Since we have the urge to eat, we can eat the mic, right?
食べていいんだよ。ふんふん。わかった。
You can eat it? Got it.
あとね、なんか「星」と「びっくり」だけ残してる人いる。え？変な人間！変な人間！
Some people only leave "hoshi" (star) and "bikkuri" (surprise)! Weird humans!
それさ、タグとかめちゃ使いづらいよ。使いづらい、えぐさし。
That makes tagging really hard to use!
ね、エゴサのしやすさで大事。大事、めちゃ大事。マジで大事。
Ease of use for Egosazu is important!
使いやすさとかね。普段から使いやすいやすさにしたいよね。
Ease of use and usability are important, right?
ちょっと1個さ、聞いていい？「あそまわ」はさ、カタカナで遊んで、まああのひらがな回と、全部ひらがなとどっちがいいかちょっとさ、今みんなのあれ聞いてみていい？
Let's listen to everyone's opinions on whether "Asobita" should be katakana or hiragana.
それもなんか結構分かれるなって今ちょっと見てて思ったから。確かに「あそまわ」でもやっぱりあのね一時変換しないのが楽なのよ。
It makes you realize they differ. "Asobita" -> maybe switching is easier.
まあそうなんだよね。ひらがな「あそまわ」は楽なのよじゃ。
Ah, that's true. Hiragana "asomawa" is easy.
ひらがな「あそまわ」かわいいよね。
Hiragana "asomawa" is cute.
「あそびたい」もまだあるね。「あそびたい」あるね。
"Asobitai" is still there. "Asobitai" is also good.
「あそびたい」は打ちやすいか結構ね。打ちやすい。打ちやすいよね。
"Asobitai" is easy to type, right?
あとね、まだ1個残ってるんじゃよ。今「あそびた」と「あたい」と「あそまわ」とあと1個の枠が残ってるんじゃが。
So we have "Asobitai", "Atai", "Asomawa", and one slot left.
何がいいかなの。
What would be good?
ひらがな「あそまわ」可愛いからじゃあ、候補ひらがなにしよう。よし、ひらがな「あそまわ」に。
"Asobimawa" in hiragana is cute, so let's make it a candidate.
「あそまわ」は分かりやすいしね。
"Asomawa" is easy to remember.
なんかどんどんさ「アリアンタイ」増えてきたんだけど。いや、しかもさ、たまになんか「エリートたい」もいるんだけど。
And more "Arientai" are increasing, plus "Elite-tai".
どういうことですか？違いますよ。
What do you mean? That's not it!
え、ふざけてエイリアンタイ入れたら1位になっちゃうからな。
If I jokingly put "Alien" in, I'd take first place.
やばいやばいやばい
No, no, no!
ダメダメダメダメ、か。
No, no, no, huh.
座れるもんね、らしい表情がね。
We get to sit, so that's fitting.
座れる座れる。ソフィアが1位さんになって、チームにょろはカンヤダ！
We can sit! Sofia took 1st place, so Team Nyoro is on top!
これちょっともう今日歌枠でもうね、完全に
Since today is a singing stream, completely...
ウマピョイ頑張ったもんね。
Umapyoi worked hard, right?
そうだよ！頑張ったのもすごかったもん。そこでカツレツすいません、
That's right! You worked so hard, it was amazing. And cutlet... excuse me,
使い終わりました。
I've used up my usage.
ソフィア、相当カツレツのね、必要な曲をね、いっぱい歌ったもんね。韓国曲ね。
Sofia, you sang a lot of songs that needed cutlet energy, right? Korean songs.
確かにね。
That's true.
確かに！ありがとう。ごめんね。ふう。
That's right! Thank you. Sorry. Whew.
うんうんうんうん。いいよ、ふにゃふにゃしてて。ふにゃふにゃ、すな、ふにゃふにゃ、ふにゃ。
Mm-hm. It's fine, being all squishy. Squishy, don't, squishy, squishy.
よっば、遊びたいかな？
Yoppa, do you want to play?
うん、遊びたっぽいね。うん。おーのわ遊びたいだね。うん、じゃあ
Yeah, looks like she wants to play. Right? O-no wants to play. Yeah, then
アンケート するのじゃ。
Let's do a poll.
ね、なんかもうさ、コイルっていうさ、ちょっと危なさそうなワードが出てきたんだけど、コイルはちょっと
Hey, also, "Coil" came up, which sounds kind of dangerous, but Coil is a bit...
いや、コイル1位にするやつじゃろ。そうそうそうそうそうそう。
No, it's the guy who puts Coil in 1st place! Right, right, right, right.
よかった変な、やばい選択肢入れなくてよかった。
Good thing we didn't put weird, dangerous choices in.
ちゃんとね、あの、どれが選ばれてもいい選択肢4択ご用意いたしました。
I properly prepared 4 choices where whichever is picked is fine.
じゃあ、アンケートをちょっと今からやるから、時間区切ろっか。
So, we'll do a poll right now, let's set a time limit.
どうしよう、5、59分までとか、3分間とかでやるか。
What should we do, until 59 minutes or 3 minutes or so?
スタート！ 今からアンケート送信しますから！
Start! We're sending out the survey right now!
え、これ、スペルも入れられるやつですか？入れられないやつですか？
Wait, can you type spelling in this? Or can't you?
これを、わしの画面だから、わししか入れられない。
Since this is my screen, only I can enter it.
ああ、なるほどね。
Ah, I see.
じゃあ、ここは、やっぱ皆さんにゆだねよ。
Well, then, let's leave it to everyone.
あ、そうかね。
Oh, is that so?
ねえ。
Right?
だってつーちゃんもあたいに1票入れてるんだから。
After all, Tsu-chan also voted for me.
え、そうだよ。
Eh, that's right.
あ、そうだよ。えでも、えでも個人的には遊びたいは、やっぱ好きだな。
Ah, that's right. But personally, I still like "want to play."
えでもなんかどれでもね、いい感じだから、ここで決まるって結構
But you know, whichever it is, it's a good vibe, so deciding here is quite...
いや、ドキドキするね。
Man, it's heart-pounding.
ドキドキする！確かに。
Heart-pounding! True.
どれになるかな？
I wonder which one it'll be?
どれになってもいいからな。
Whichever it is is fine, though.
これ、どうやったらさ、更新できるの？いま、わしたちの画面、ゼロ票になってるけど。
How do you refresh this? Right now, our screens show zero votes.
上がっていくはずだよね？
It should go up, right?
うん、上がっていくはず。あれ、投票できな、って言ってる？
Yeah, it should go up. Wait, can you not vote?
どこで、これ？大丈夫そう？
Where is this? Is it okay?
でも眠りたい人もいるよ。
But there are people who want to put it in.
入れた人いる？入れた？入れた！あ、入れてる人いるな。
Are there people who put it in? Did you? Put it? Ah, there are people who put it in.
ちょっとじゃあ、もう1回起動するの？
So let's reboot it again?
そう、でもなんかちょっとラグラグしたりしちゃうらしいから、しょうがないのかも知れない。
Yeah, but apparently it lags a bit, so it might be unavoidable.
そういう感じか。
Is that how it is?
あ、じゃあちょっと、ちょっと待ってやるのはじゃ。
Then, wait a bit, doing it after waiting a bit.
3分間？
3 minutes?
待ってやる。
Wait and do it.
アンケートバグ？アンケートバグってる？
Survey bug? Is the survey bugged?
あ、バグってるんだ。じゃあもう1回出してみるか。
Ah, it's bugged. Then let's try putting it out again.
じゃあ、アンケートもう1回やるね。ごめんね、のじゃ。
Then, we'll do the survey again. Sorry, noja.
入れてくれた人ごめんね。
Sorry to those who put it in.
のじゃ、もう1回入れてね。
Noja, put it in again, please.
あれ？ちょっと待ってね。
Huh? Wait a minute.
あ、こっちがバグって るってこと？入れたのに、みんなのが反映されてなかっていう感じなんだ。
Ah, so this side is bugged? Even though we entered it, everyone's isn't reflecting.
なるほどなるほど。
I see, I see.
じゃあ、ちょっとじゃあ一旦終了するのじゃ。
Then, let's end it once.
待って。のじゃ、のじゃ、のじゃ！がんばれ。
Wait. Noja, noja, noja! Do your best.
あれ？
Huh?
あ、でもなんか、は、1.8万票入ってるよ。
Ah, but 18,000 votes are in.
え、入ってる？
Eh, it's in?
あ、よかったよかった！ありがとうみんな。
Ah, good, good! Thank you everyone.
え、入ってるけど、これ、もう1回？
Eh, it's in, but should we do it again?
もう1回、あの、やっぱ59分までって言っ |
Again, like I said until 59 minutes...
そう、そうだよね。
Right, right.
じゃあ、もう1回、えっと
Then, one more time, um...
え、まてなんて入れたか忘れちゃった。
Wait, I forgot what I put in.
あ、ここにここに載ってるよ。
Ah, it's listed right here.
あ、あそび…あ、あ、あそびたい、あ、俺間違えちゃった。
Ah, "want to play"... ah, I made a mistake...
流れ弾、流れ弾。
Stray bullet, stray bullet.
え、で覚えてる。任せろ。
Eh, I remember. Leave it to me.
ちょっと待ってね。
Wait a minute.
いまから頑張ってタイピングする。おにしろもうちょっと待っててくれる？
I'll type hard now. Onishiro, can you wait a little longer?
待っててね。
Wait for me.
もう1回同じアンケート取ります。
We'll take the same survey again.
えす。
Yes.
あそびた、えっと、あ、あそびたい
Want to play, um, ah, want to play...
あたい、あたい、あたい！
Atai, atai, atai!
なんか、いま最後の投票前の悪足掻きしてる人たちがいる。
Some people are struggling right before the final vote.
え？
Eh?
あそびた、あそびたい、あたい、
Asobita, asobitai, atai,
なんじゃ、あたい？あそまわ？
What is it, atai? Asomawa?
あ、あそまわ？ひらがな。
Ah, asomawa? In hiragana.
よし！もう1回行くのじゃ！よっしゃ！よっしゃ！
Alright! Let's go again! Yay! Yay!
これで、これでいけるかな？
Can we make it with this?
さすがにいけてほしいのじゃ！いけてくれ！
I hope we can make it! Make it happen!
あ、来た来た来た来た！あ、おにしろ！
Ah, it's here! Ah, Onishiro!
いけるいける！はや！はや！
We can do it! Fast!
早いよ。
So fast.
よし、じゃあ、時間は22、どうしようか。22時までに する？
Alright, then, time is 22... what should we do? Make it until 22:00?
そうしよっか。
Let's do that.
22時になったら切ろうと思いますの。
When it hits 22:00, we'll cut it off, I think.
じゃあ、わしの手元の時計じゃからね、おにしろの時計じゃないよ。
So, it's my watch, not Onishiro's watch, okay?
うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
わしが判断するからね。
Because I'll be the one judging.
めらち基準で。
Based on Melachi's standards.
どうしよう、わしの時計が5時間遅れてる。
What should I do, my watch is 5 hours behind.
いや、待てるよ全然5時間。
No, we can totally wait 5 hours.
本当？じゃあ、5時間わしたちと一緒にいてくれる？
Really? Then will you stay with us for 5 hours?
いけるか？耐久配信じゃん。やっちゃうか？
Can we do it? It's an endurance stream. Shall we do it?
ぜんぜん、いまやっと喉慣れてきたからいけるけど、だから
Totally, my throat just got used to it, so we can do it, but...
あ、こっから？こっから歌っちゃうか、5時間？
Ah, from here? Shall we sing for 5 hours from here?
歌っちゃうか！
Let's sing!
そんな。
No way.
ぶっ飛ばしていくか。そんな、なんか、わし冗談で言ったら
Let's blow right through it. Like, when I jokingly said,
なんかこの人たち本当にしそうで怖いのは。
it's scary because these guys might actually do it.
だって、うち ら、あ・そ・び・ま・わ・り・たーい！
Because we... want to play around!
これね、遊び回りいたいゲームね。
This is a game where we want to play around.
鳥合いなんだよ。
It's a scramble.
そして そして そして、えっとね、
And, and, and... um,
まだね わしの時計ね なってない 十時
my clock isn't at 10:00 yet.
もうちょっと あとね 見てあげよう どれこれ
Let's wait just a little bit longer and see.
駆け込みだよみんな、あとちょっとだよ。
Come on everyone, time's running out!
本当に？ あとね、3秒！
Really? Only 3 seconds left!
3、2、1！ みんなみんな！急いで急いで！
3, 2, 1! Everyone, hurry, hurry!
終了——！
Time's up!
はい！ 結果は、えー、遊びたい52％と——！
Okay! The results are: 52% want to play—!
おおー！ 結構ダントツ！
Whoa! That's a landslide!
ね、ダントツだったね、すごいうれしい。
Right? A total landslide, I'm so happy.
はい、ちょっと固定コメントにしておこう。
Right, let's pin this as a comment.
略称は、略称は遊び、遊び遊び、遊び遊びたいに決まったのじゃ。
The abbreviation was decided to be "asobi" (play), play, play, play-play-play!
ついに決まったのじゃ。ありがとみんな決めてくれて、ありがと！
It's finally decided! Thank you everyone for deciding, thank you!
投票してくれてありがとなのじゃ。ありがとありがと！
Thank you for voting. Thank you, thank you!
2.1万票だって！ そんなにいっぱいさ……
21,000 votes! With that many...
そんなにいっぱいためたらさ、かなりさ、これあれじゃない？ソピア統計的に正しい値なんじゃない？
If we gathered that many, isn't this statistically accurate for Sopia?
確かに、募集団的に確かにいける。これは民意と言っても過言ではない！よっ！
True, for the population size, we can definitely do it. This is no exaggeration to call the public will! Yeah!
よっしゃー！ 科学的裏付けが、裏付けもあるのじゃ！
All right! There's scientific backing and proof too!
じゃあ我々「遊びたい」と名乗っていくのじゃ。
So from now on, we'll call ourselves "Asobitai" (Want to Play).
カタカナ「遊びたい」ね。エゴサも遊びたいでもすることにするのじゃ。
In katakana "Asobitai". We'll also use "Asobitai" for egosurfing.
ハッシュタグとかもね、「#遊びたい」とかで呟いてくれてもいいかもね。
Hashtags like "#Asobitai" might be good to tweet with too.
割れるかな、どうなるかな。まあ、全部調べるから！
Will it split? What will happen? Well, we'll check everything!
パワーなのじゃ。うちらのエゴサの鬼だからね。
It's about power. Because we're egosurfing demons.
あ、お主らさ、お主らのフォロワーにも教えてあげてよ。「#遊びタイ」遊びたいの略称「遊びたいになったらしいよ」みたいなのをさ、呟いてさ、フォロワーに教えてあげよう。
Oh, and you guys, tell your followers too! Like, "#Asobitai" abbreviated as "Asobitai" became a thing, tweet that and let your followers know.
お願いしまーす！ お願いしまーす！
Please do! Please do!
のじゃー！ ふーん。
Noja! Hmm.
よしよしよしよし。そして名前が決まったところで、
Good, good, good. And now that the name is decided,
やっぱりお主らさ、せっかく集まってるんじゃから、4人全員の歌ってるどこ見たくない？
since you guys gathered here after all, wouldn't you want to see all four of us singing?
見たい！ 見たい！
We want to! We want to!
お主が歌うんじゃよ！ 私たちが歌うんじゃよ！
You guys are going to sing! We are going to sing!
みんなのね、みんなの民意を代弁させていただいた。見たいよね？ 見たい！ 見たい！
We represented everyone's public will. You want to see it, right? We want to! We want to!
やっぱさ、4人で歌うならさ、ぴったりの曲がある気がするんじゃが。
You know, if four of us are singing, I feel like there's the perfect song for it.
なんだなんだ？ なんじゃと思う？
What is it? What do you think it is?
最高な曲があるのじゃ。
There's an ultimate song.
お主らもきっと知ってるんじゃないの？ 知っててほしいな！知ってほしいのじゃ！
You guys probably know it too, right? I want you to know it! I want you to know it!
よし、じゃあ夜も遅くなってきたし、歌っちゃおうかな！
Alright, well, it's getting late at night, so shall we sing it?!
お水とか平気お主ら。飲むか？
Are you guys okay with water? Want a drink?
ごくごく。ふーまーまー。
Gulp gulp. Fu-ma-ma-ma.
エコー？
Echo?
エコー！
Echo!
エコーです。ごきげんよう。
It's echo. Good day.
ふふふふふ。
Hehehehe.
よしよしよしよし。それでは、お主ら、
Good, good, good. Well then, you guys,
よしよしに反応した。よしよしタントがよしよしに反応した。
responded to "yoshi-yoshi". Yoshi-yoshi tonto responded to yoshi-yoshi.
お姉さんだったのじゃ？ のじゃ？ おいとくか。よし！
Was it an older sister? Noja? Let's leave it. Alright!
ということで、みんなでタイトルコールしちゃう？ しよ——！ 聞いてください、せーの！ 「騒げ！ぐるぐるタイム！」
With that, shall we do a group title call? Let's do it! Please listen, ready—! "Sawage! Guru Guru Time!"
騒げ！限界時間
Shout out! Time is limited!
ドラムの音が鳴った 遊びの天才たちは大集結
The drums beat, genius players gather together!
ゲーム おしゃべり カラオケ そのまま 即興ライブ
Games, chatting, karaoke, and an impromptu live show right there!
ラララララ 扉を開けろ
La la la la la, open the door!
行くぞお前ら
Let's go, you guys!
お待たせしました メンタルむきむき正義マン
Sorry to keep you waiting, mentally ripped justice man!
ヒノヨーチン ヒノヨーチン
Hinoyochin, hinoyochin!
きらこに ときこ カジノの本拠
Kirako, Tokiko, the casino's stronghold!
郵便屋さんから 音が届いた
Sound arrived from the postman!
めめめ お腹が空いたなら 野菜を食べた
Mememe, if you're hungry, eat your vegetables!
小さな一歩 未来へきっと
A small step, surely toward the future!
地球は青いように新月でレッツゴー
The Earth is blue, let's go on a new moon!
手と手合わせて 心重ねた
Putting hands together, overlapping our hearts!
最強の仲間たちがここに集まったのなら ぐるぐるタイムはじめよう
If the strongest comrades have gathered here, let's start the guru-guru time!
ぐるぐるもうっしゅあばれろ 遊びの宇宙
Spin around, rampage, the universe of play!
世界を洗え
Wash away the world,
今日もアジトで騒ごう
Let's cause a ruckus in our hideout today too!
うちら遊びまわりたい！
We wanna run around and play!
同じアホなら遊ばにゃ損々
If we're all fools, it's a loss not to play!
ワンコそばなら食べなきゃ損々
If it's wanko soba, it's a loss not to eat!
からくりポップのシッタルマチ
Karakuri Pop's Shittaru Machi,
眠気なんて泡たち 客は総立ち おどれパパラッチ
Sleepiness bubbles up, the crowd stands, dance, paparazzi!
まいっか！
Whatever!
ぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐる 踊りましょう！はい！
Spinning round and round... Let's dance! Yes!
雑多な日々に日常を追い求め
Chasing daily life amidst bustling days,
最強の仲間たちがここに集まったのなら
If the strongest comrades have gathered here,
回り回る世界はきっとうちらとともに！
The spinning world will surely be with us!
ぐるぐるタイム始めよう
Let's start the guruguru time!
ぐるぐるもうし暴れろ
Guruguru mouse, go wild!
遊びの渦で世界は洗え
Wash the world in the vortex of play!
今日もアジトで騒げっぞい！
Let's make noise in our hideout today too!
ぐるぐるタイム奏でよう
Let's play the guruguru time!
ぐるぐるもうし弾けろ
Guruguru mouse, pop out!
初めじゃ楽しい わちゃわちゃ嬉しい
For the first time it's fun, bustling and happy,
今日もアジトで騒ごう うちら遊びまわりたい！
Let's make noise in our hideout today, we want to play around!
いつまでも楽しみたい 君も遊びまわりたい！
I want to enjoy it forever, you want to play around too!
騒げぐるぐるタイムでした！
That was 'Sawage Guruguru Time'!
聞いてくれてありがとうなのじゃー！
Thank you so much for listening!
お主らはこの曲知ってた？
Did you guys know this song?
もちろん知ってくれてるよね。
Of course you know it.
知っててほしい！
I want you to know it!
生方で言うとね、初めてじゃったな。
Speaking of live performances, it's our first, right?
そうだよ、初めてだ！
That's right, it's our first!
ねえ、緊張するね。
Man, we're so nervous.
超楽しかったよね！
It was super fun!
難しかったよね！
It was hard, right?
やばかったよね！
It was crazy!
ライブとかめっちゃ盛り上がりそう！
Concerts and stuff are gonna be super hype!
盛り上がっちゃう！絶対盛り上がっちゃう！
We'll get hyped! Definitely get hyped!
うん、いつかライブで歌いたいな！
Yeah, I wanna sing it at a live show someday!
歌いたいな！歌いたいよ！
Wanna sing it! Wanna sing it!
うん、それでさ、ライブで歌ったあとさ、この初めてのさ、あのみんなで歌ったこの歌アフリで聞いて、あ、こんなこともあったなってなるんじゃよ。
And after singing it at a live show, listening to this song we sang together afterwards makes you go, 'Ah, those things happened too.'
劇エモ！劇エモだ！
Super emotional! So emotional!
劇エモだ。
Super emotional.
泣けてきた。
I'm gonna cry.
早い早い。
Too fast, too fast.
涙は取っておくのじゃ。
Save your tears.
はい、ぐるぐるタイム歌わせていただきましたけどそろそろねおひらきの時間にしようと思うんじゃが、えー！
We had you listen to 'Guruguru Time', but we're thinking of wrapping things up soon, eh?!
お知らせタイムしちゃおうかなって思うからさ、お主らもうちょっと付き合ってよ。
So we're gonna do an announcement time, bear with us a bit longer.
お願いします！
Please!
お知らせさせてほしいのじゃー！
We want you to let us make announcements!
ええとね、そう、早速ね、ちょっと、どこに出すのがいいんじゃろうか。このへんに出す？ちょっとツチノコワシは隠れるけどいい？
Uh, right, let's see, where should we put it? Around here? Tsuchinoko Washi will be hidden, is that okay?
いいよ。頑張って上向いといて。上向いといて。
It's fine. Do your best looking up. Look up.
はい、ええと、オリジナル曲「騒げ！ぐるぐるタイム」遊びたい公式チャンネルにて公開中です！さっきの曲聴いて、うわ、また聴きたいなって思ったら、ぜひ何度もMVと合わせて聴いてください！
Our original song 'Sawage! Guruguru Time' is public on the official Asobi Mawaritai channel! If you wanna hear it again, please listen along with the MV!
次、え、スターティングボイスが、私たち初の発売中ですのでのじゃー！英語と日本語両方ともあるのでかなりグローバルなボイスになってるんじゃないかなと思います。
Next, our first Starting Voices are on sale! Since there are both English and Japanese versions, it's a pretty global voice pack.
おはようボイス、おやすみボイス、その他たくさんいろんなバリエーションのボイスが楽しめますのでぜひお手手に取ってください！
You can enjoy Good Morning, Good Night voices, and many more variations, so please pick it up!
そして動く壁紙！動く壁紙、早速もう壁紙にしてくれてるよって人もいっぱいいると思うんじゃが、我々のライブ2DPVのね、イラストをね、壁紙にしましたのでこちらもぜひ合わせてお手手に取っていただけると嬉しいですのじゃー！
And moving wallpapers! Many of you have already set it as wallpaper, but since we made our live 2DPV illustrations into wallpapers, we'd be happy if you pick those up too!
そして次こちら、レギュラーアウトフィットグッズですのじゃー！缶バッジとアクリルスタンド、私たち初期印象のね、初期、初期っぽいです？あの1番スタンダードなお顔のね、書かれてる缶バッジとアクリルスタンドが発売中ですのでのじゃー！常設グッズっぽいのですが見、まあ今のうちにね、早めに手に入れて
And next is Regular Outfit goods! Badges and acrylic stands featuring our standard faces are on sale! They seem permanent, but get them early,
いろんなところに連れてってくれてもいいんじゃないかなと、思いますの。
...and have them take you to various places, I think that would be nice, so...
じゃあ、よろしくお願いします！
So, let's make it happen. Thank you!
そして遊びに行きたいのデビュー記念グッズですの、じゃあ。
And these are the debut commemorative goods to celebrate going out and about, you see!
えっとね、これなんじゃっけ？あっ、パネル？アクリルパネルと缶バッジとかTシャツとか、とにかくいろいろ...
Um, what was this again? An acrylic panel? Acrylic panels, can badges, T-shirts, and all sorts of things...
ありますので、こちらも、あの、遊びに行きたいのグッズのページ見てみてほしいですの、じゃあ！
...are available, so please check out the goods page for going out, too, you see!
よろしくお願いします！
Please do!
そしてホロカ！ホロカ！こいでっか！こいでっか！
And the Holoca! The Holoca, look at this, look at this!
あの、もう予約販売が始まってるっぽくて、
Um, it looks like advance sales have already started,
もう早速予約したよって人も見てますの、じゃあぜひぜひ、あの、手に入れてくれると嬉しいですの、じゃ！
and we've even seen people saying they've already pre-ordered, so please, please get your hands on them, you see!
そしてこっからはちょっと口頭での告知になってしまうんじゃが、誰からいく？
And from here, we have some verbal announcements, but who goes first?
じゃあ、時系列順に行くか。
Well, let's go in chronological order!
時系列？
Chronological order?
ってことは？
That means...
アタイラ？アタイラだ！アタイラだ！
Ataira! Ataira, right?
アタイラだ。はい。
Ataira's team!
アタイラだね。
Right!
けっこうな、けっこうな告知じゃよな、これもう。
Quite a... quite a big announcement this is, too!
えっと、アタイラ暖色さんチーム！
Um, Ataira's warm colors team!
はい。なんと、10月の6日、火曜日、
And, what, October 6th, Tuesday,
あんど、7日？7日かな？
and... 7th? 7th, maybe?
水曜日にかけて、
...spanning into Wednesday,
オーバーウォッチ 50勝するまで耐久配信を行います！
we will be holding our 50-win endurance stream on Overwatch!
耐久だよ！
An endurance stream!
え、あのさ、わしオーバーウォッチ知らないんだけども、
Um, you know, I don't really know Overwatch,
50勝ってどれぐらいかかるの、じゃあ？
how long does 50 wins usually take, you see?
えっとね、私はもう達成してんのね。
Well, you see, I've already achieved it, you know!
やったときは、え、25時間ぐらいかかったかな？
When I did it, it took about 25 hours, I think.
え？の、じゃあ？
Eh? You see?
え、25時間かかっちゃった。
It took 25 hours?!
え、不眠？
Eh, without sleep?
えっとね、日に分けた。うん、何日かに分けてやったんだけど、合計で25時間かかったかな？
Um, you know, I split it up. I split it across a few days and did it, but it took a total of 25 hours, I think.
ええ！？
Eh?!
はい、なので、頑張るので、応援よろしくお願いします！
So, please give us your support, you see!
今日ここツルリが頑張ります！よろしくお願いします！応援してください！
Kyoko and Tsururi will do their best! Please support us!
頑張ります！配信のじゃあ、頑張ってね！
We'll do our best! An endurance stream, you see! Do your best, okay!
二人でやればもっと早いはず！
If the two of us do it together, it should be even faster!
はい！
Right!
お弁当入れとか持ってこっか？
Should we bring lunch boxes or something?
じゃあ、お手紙いっぱい届けて。
Then I'll deliver a bunch of letters.
私からあげがいい。
I want karage!
なかなかの、けっこうイカつい耐久をデビュー直後にするの？
That's quite a... quite an intense level to debut right after, you see.
ねえ、そうだよえ？うちらありえんからね。
That's right, isn't it? We couldn't possibly do that, you see!
ありえんからね。
...couldn't possibly do that, you see.
ありえん、ありえん、遊びに行きたいか。なるほどね。
Impossible, impossible, we'd want to go out and play, right? I see, I see.
でもいっぱい頑張ってきてるよ！ありえんすごっ！
Even so, you've been working really hard, you know! You're amazing!
頑張るね！頑張れ！
We'll do our best!
50勝してやろう！
We'll get those 50 wins!
するぞ！
Let's do it!
じゃあ、わしたちの感触さんチームのコラボの発表もしちゃおうかな。
Next up, we should probably announce the collab for Washi's Karashiki team, too, right?
知りたい！
We wanna know!
じゃあわしから言うね。
So Washi will tell you, you see!
はい！
Got it!
えっと、ちょっと感触さんがけっこう、あの、重めじゃから、わしたちにも期待されるとちょっとそこまでは返せないんじゃが...
Um, the Karashiki team is quite on the heavy side, so we can't really expect much from Washi's team, you see...
あの、すっごく優しく軽めのコラボなんじゃが、
...it's going to be a super sweet and light collab, you see!
えっと、10月の8日、8日の木曜日に、何時だっけ？えっとね、20時かな？8日の20時から、えっと、アチシメらのチャンネルで、ソフィアと遊びたいぜんで戦いますの、じゃあ！
It'll take place on October 8th, the 8th, which is a Thursday, starting at... what time was it? Um, 8 PM, right? On October 8th at 8 PM, we'll be playing on Sophia's channel with the "Sophia & Want to Go Out" Zen Team, you see!
行きたい！
Wanna go!
やっぱ、遊びに行きたいって名乗ってる以上ね、遊びたいぜんは是非ともやっておきたいゲーム、
We really want to go out and play, so we definitely want to do this, you see! It's a game we really want to play,
是非とも戦いたい、あの、
and we really want to battle.
運のアチチメらと、しの、スラシナソフィアということで、最終決戦ね！
It's Un no Achichi Melatou... no, Chino Sura-shina Sophia, so it's the final battle, you see!
ホロカではね、ボロ負けしたんで、
We suffered a crushing defeat in Holoca,
ボロ負けした。
so we lost.
今度こそはリベンジをね、誓ってます。
This time for sure, we've sworn to get our revenge, you see!
したいと思いますの、じゃあ！
So we want to win, you see!
そしてソフィアからも告知があるんだよね。
And Sophia has an announcement, too, you see!
はーい！ということで、その翌日、10月9日金曜日、スラシナソフィアのチャンネルで、
Right! So, the very next day, October 9th, Friday, on Chino Sura-shina Sophia's channel...
はい、イグノーベル賞クイズ企画をやらせていただきます、ウィズ遊びに行きたい！という事で！
...we will be holding the "Ig Nobel Prize Quiz Competition, with Want to Go Out", you see!
おぉー、楽しみだ！
Oh, how exciting!
次の4人コラボがそこかな？そうだね、そうだね。
The next 4-person collab will be that one, right? That's right, right?
はい、夜6時から、10月9日夜6時から、そう、イグノーベル賞って、みんな知ってるかな？
Right, starting at 6 PM on October 9th, do you all know about the Ig Nobel Prize?
うーん。
Hmm.
そもそも、そのノーベル賞というものがございまして、
Well, basically, there is this thing called the Nobel Prize,
聞いたことある？
you've probably heard of it, right?
あるある、あるある。ノーベル賞はある。
Yes, yes, we know, we know. The Nobel Prize, yes.
なんかね、すごいね、いろんな研究とかいろんな形で、その人類に貢献した人に与えられるのがノーベル賞なんだけど、
It's given to people who have contributed to humanity in various ways through research and such, but the Ig Nobel Prize...
そのパロディ賞っていうのがイグノーベル賞で、
...is a parody of that, you see—the Ig Nobel Prize!
パロディ？
Parody?
そうそうそうそう。
Right, right, right.
なので、あの、ノーベル賞とはまた違って、人々を笑わせて、で、さらに考えさせるような、ま、そんな研究とかね、取り組みに対して与えられる賞をイグノーベル賞って言って、
So, unlike the Nobel Prize, the Ig Nobel Prize is awarded for research and efforts that make people laugh and then make them think even more, you see!
そう、けっこうね、面白い、なんか、あの、モンバットは、四角いウンチをするとか、そういう、
It's got some really interesting... like, doing stupid poop research or something—
何それ？！
What is that?!
おもしろ！
Funny!
えっ、そう、そういうことを、なんか、明らかにした人にイグノーベル賞が与えられたりとか、そういうね、ちょっとユニークな、
things like that, where people made those weird things clear, and they get awarded the Ig Nobel Prize—it's got some really unique...
その研究に関する賞に関する、ちょっとね、クイズを、この3人に出したいかと思っているのて、
research-related quizzes, quizzes about those kinds of prizes, we want to give to these three, you see!
え、もう続き気になるもんだって！
Wait, I'm already curious about the rest!
超面白いのじゃん！
That sounds so interesting!
イグノーベル賞！
The Ig Nobel Prize!
なんか楽しそう面白そう。
Sounds like so much fun!
てかワクワクするクイズに答えるってこと?
Wait, does that mean answering exciting quizzes?
超ワクワク!
Super exciting!
えーどういうこと? クイズ番組なんかテレビみたいで憧れなのだジャン!
Eh, what does that mean? Quiz shows feel like TV, I've always admired them, jan!
めちゃわかる! 超楽しみ! 楽しみなのだジャン!
So relatable! Super looking forward to it! Looking forward to it, jan!
うん。ということで、またね、次の、4人コラボ10月9日9時からあさひなそぴあチャンネルでやりますので、ぜひぜひまた遊びに来てね! のいちゃんだよー!
Yeah. So, also, the next 4-person collab is on Oct 9 at 9 PM on Asahina Sopia's channel, so please come play again! It's Noi-chan!
はい! 他にはお知らせある人いる? 大丈夫かな?
Yes! Are there any other announcements? Is everyone okay?
大丈夫? うん、大丈夫。
Okay? Yeah, okay.
はい! えーと、遊びまわりたい! えーと、デビューして1週間とちょっと。
Yes! Um, I want to go around playing! It's been a little over a week since debut.
これからも私たちをもっともっと応援よろしくお願いします! お願いします!
From now on, please keep supporting us more and more! Please do!
あの途中から歌ってみたよって人はもう一回最初から、最初から4人全員の歌ってみたアーカイブ聴いてくれると嬉しいですのだジャン!
If you heard the singing cover halfway, we'd love for you to listen to the archive from the start, jan!
みんな最高だったから本当に! 見てほしい。個性あったの。みたいないい感じで、
Everyone was amazing, really! I want you to see it. Each had their own vibe.
今日はそろそろお開きに...
Today, it's about time to wrap up.
今来たばかり?
Just got here?
寂しい。寂しいけど、アーカイブでさ、いつでも会えるからさ。
Lonely, but you can always catch us on the archive, so.
確かに出ると思うから、お前らそちらもチェックしてみてほしいですのだジャン!
True! Tomorrow's schedule will be on Twitter too, so please check it out, jan!
のいちゃんだよ! じゃあ最後は挨拶をね、えっと「次も遊びまわりー」って言ったらみんなで「たー!」っていう挨拶をするよ!
It's Noi-chan! For the final greeting, when I say "Next time, playing aroundー", we'll do the greeting!
いいかの準備いいかの? ばっちり! ばっちり! よし!
Is everyone ready? Spot on! Spot on! Alright!
じゃあ最後の挨拶いきますのだジャン! 次もみんなで遊びまわりー! たーー!
Then final greeting, jan! Next time, everyone, playing aroundー! ー!